# **Curriculum Vitae**

**Personal** 

Name Alistair Turnbull

Address 1 Rectory Court, Clungunford, Craven Arms, Shropshire, SY7 OPN, United Kingdom

Telephone+44 (0)7584 034223 (Mobile)Email Addressalistairturnbull@aol.comDate of Birth17th October 1973StatusMarried, 1 Child

Nationality British

**Education** 

2007 Masters in Business Administration, IMD, Lausanne, Switzerland (graduated with honours).

2004-2005 Diploma in EC Competition Law, King's College, London (merit pass).
1991-1995 Bachelor of Laws (Honours), University of Edinburgh (Upper Second Class).

**Executive Summary** 

Dynamic executive with over 10 years experience in medtech, FMCG and legal service industries with strong analytical and problem solving skills. Significant experience of working cross-culturally and functionally in executing strategic M&A and transaction-led change

**Work Experience** 

2008- March 2010

### Leica Microsystems, Heerbrugg, Switzerland

## **Business Development Director, Surgical and Industry Divisions**

First Business Development Director of two divisions of leading microscope manufacturer (combined revenues of \$0.3bn), reporting to Global Leica VP of Business Development and divisional managing directors. Responsible for driving inorganic growth strategy and execution, brokering strategic technology collaborations with external partners and market intelligence and benchmarking

- *Inorganic strategy*: Created first inorganic growth roadmaps for each division following comprehensive primary and secondary market research on served and near adjacent market opportunities including numerous interviews with key customer opinion leaders. Took 3 of these opportunities through to advanced stages of valuation/approval.
- **Deal cultivation and execution**: Increased the 3 yr revenue growth potential of Industry Division by 15% (at peak forecasted sales) through the cultivation and execution of two strategic licensing transactions.
- *Open innovation*: Worked together with R&D to identify and then broker relationships with technology outsource partners. Took 2 of these discussions to heads of terms.
- **Core strategy**: seconded by divisional board as a troubleshooter on a number of critical strategic issues requiring strong analytical skills and/or market validation
  - Produced an in depth, market-led/quantified assessment of product development activities of Leica's major competitor which led to a reprioritization of Leica's own product development priorities
  - Produced detailed assessment and recommendations of strategic issues around core US channel of Surgical Division which strongly influenced the shape a channel reorganization conducted by US management in 2008/9.
  - Assisted Leica Surgical Marketing Director in revising Leica's go to market strategy following the unsuccessful launch of a new innovative product. Targeted segment approach resulted in 5 fold sales increase in 3 months following implementation.

2003-2006

2005-2006

#### Scottish & Newcastle plc, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

### Project Manager, Commercial Strategy, S&N UK (on secondment from Group Legal)

Execution specialist within 4 person special strategic projects team of £1.6bn UK subsidiary of Scottish & Newcastle plc. Reported to UK Strategy Director..

- KNDL Joint Venture: Led day to day project management, structuring, legal negotiations (on
  corporate, banking and outsourcing contracts) and advice to senior executive team in largest
  outsourcing project in S&N's history, involving the transfer of a circa £250m cost base and 3000
  employees to a debt-financed scaleable logistics joint venture and the delivery of £30m cost
  savings.
- **Disposal of Courage brand portfolio**: Negotiated the £10m sale of Courage portfolio through joint venture structure that delivered to S&N future value participation and control of brand in key strategic channels.
- Disposal of Becks brand portfolio: Project managed post-sale handover of UK sales activity, leading 30 strong team across sales, finance, marketing and distribution functions achieving a seamless customer and operational handover.

2003-2005

### Senior Legal Adviser, Group Legal Services, S&N plc

Corporate/M&A specialist within 4 person in-house group legal team reporting to Head of Group Legal and General Counsel. Specific responsibility for supporting corporate development and other senior executives in management and negotiation of large acquisitions and disposals, joint ventures, and shareholder disputes.

- Sale of S&N Retail pub estate: led the legal process and negotiations of £2.51bn multi-party auction, S&N's largest ever corporate transaction, including associated beer supply agreements and transitional service arrangements. Managed 20 strong cross-functional internal disclosure team and external legal spend of over £10m.
- Investment in United Breweries (Kingfisher Beer): Led legal negotiations and due diligence in S&N's \$180m investment in No. 1 Indian brewer United Breweries Limited and associated cross-licensing/distribution agreements of key brands. Worked flexibly under extreme time pressure to deliver deal and frustrate rival competitive bid.
- BBH Joint Venture: Produced various notes of advice on a number of issues within JV agreement between S&N and Carlsberg as well as acting from time to time as board secretary. Analysis of shotgun provisions of JV agreement formed basis of key strand of S&N's takeover defence in 2007.

1998-2003

#### Clifford Chance LLP, London, United Kingdom

## Associate, Private Equity

- Senior corporate associate on £700m LBO of Travelodge UK and Little Chef by Permira in 2002.
   Project managed 7 UK based functional teams through due diligence, contract negotiation and execution phases of deal in addition to drafting and negotiating key acquisition and investment documentation.
- Senior corporate associate on €400m LBO of Aventis Animal Nutrition by CVC Capital in 2002.
   Project managed due diligence team of over 70 specialists across 14 jurisdictions and 8 time zones in addition to negotiating investment documentation.
- Led customer relationship team with key client Permira.

1996-1998

#### McGrigor Donald LLP, Glasgow

Traineeship in Scotland's leading commercial law firm.

Languages

English (mother tongue), German (highly competent), French (basic conversational)

**Professional Qualifications** 

Scottish qualified solicitor (since 1998)

Interests

Food, wine and music (French horn player and choir member)